window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Engineering_Mathematics - Engineering_Mathematics — Slot 4 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Engineering_Mathematics — Slot 4",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Let u and v be two vectors in \\(R^{2}\\) whose Euclidean norms satisfy ||u||=2|| v|| . What is the value of \\(\\alpha\\) such that w=u+\\(\\alpha\\)v bisects the angle between u and v ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(1/2\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(-1/2\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>2</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118311/gate2017-1-30#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>The value of \\(\\lim_{x\\rightarrow 1}\\frac{x^{7}-2x^{5}+1}{x^{3}-3x^{2}+2}\\) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>is 0</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>is -1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>is 1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>does not exist</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>is 1</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118309/gate2017-1-28#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Let \\(c_{1}....c_{n}\\)  be scalars, not all zero, such that \\(\\sum_{i=1}^{n}c_{i}a_{i}=0\\)<br> where \\(a_{i}\\) are column vectors in \\(R^{n}\\). Consider the set of linear equations Ax = b <br>\nwhere A=\\(a_{1}....a_{n}\\) and b=\\(\\sum_{i=1}^{n}a_{i}\\). The set of equations has <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>a unique solution at  \\(x=J_{n}\\) where \\(J_{n}\\) denotes a n-dimensional vector of all 1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>no solution</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>infinitely many solutions</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>finitely many solutions</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>infinitely many solutions</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118282/gate2017-1-3#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>\\(\\lim_{x\\rightarrow 0}\\frac{\\sqrt{1+x}-\\sqrt{1-x}}{x}\\)  is given by <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>0</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>-1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/55595/isro2016-3\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>What is the sum to infinity of the series,<br>\\(3+6 x^{2}+9 x^{4}+12 x^{6}+\\ldots \\text { given }|x| \\lt 1\\) <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{3}{(1+x^{2})}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{3}{(1+x^{2})^{2}}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{3}{(1-x^{2})^{2}}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{3}{(1-x^{2})}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{3}{(1-x^{2})^{2}}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/55594/isro2016-2\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>The value of the expression \\(13^{99}\\)(mod 17), in the range 0 to 16, is _________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "4",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39588/gate2016-2-29#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following well-formed formulae in predicate calculus is NOT valid? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\((\\forall x p(x)\\Rightarrow \\forall xq(x))\\Rightarrow (\\exists x\\neg p(x) \\vee \\forall xq(x))\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\((\\exists xp(x)\\vee \\exists xq(x))\\Rightarrow \\exists x(p(x)\\vee  q(x))\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\exists x (p(x)\\wedge q(x)) \\Rightarrow (\\exists xp(x)\\wedge \\exists xq(x))\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\forall x (p(x)\\vee q(x))\\Rightarrow (\\forall x p(x) \\vee \\forall x q(x)) \\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\forall x (p(x)\\vee q(x))\\Rightarrow (\\forall x p(x) \\vee \\forall x q(x)) \\)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39618/gate2016-2-27#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Suppose that the eigen values of matrix A are 1, 2, 4. The determinant of \\((A^{-1})^{T}\\) is _________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "0.124",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39549/gate2016-2-6#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Consider the systems,each consisting of m linear equations in n variables.<br>\nI. If m \\(\\lt\\) n, then all such systems have a solution <br>\nII. If m \\(\\gt\\) n, then none of these systems has a solution <br>\nIII. If m = n, then there exists a system which has a solution <br>\nWhich one of the following is CORRECT? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I, II and III are true</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only II and III are true</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Only III is true</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of them is true</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Only III is true</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39554/gate2016-2-4#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Let f(x) be a polynomial and g(x) = f'(x) be its derivative. If the degree of (f(x)+ f(-x)) is 10, then the degree of (g(x)-g(-x)) is ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "9",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39571/gate2016-2-2#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>The coefficient of \\(x^{12}\\) in \\((x^{3}+x^{4}+x^{5}+x^{6}+. . . )^{3}\\) is ______. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "10",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39693/gate2016-1-26#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Two eigen values of a 3x3 real matrix P are (2+\\(\\sqrt{-1}\\)) and 3.The determinantof P is __________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "15",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39634/gate2016-1-5#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>\\(\\lim_{x\\rightarrow 4}\\frac{sin(x-4)}{x-4}\\)=_________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "1",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39630/gate2016-1-3#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>If for non-zero  \\(x,af(x)+bf\\left ( \\frac{1}{x} \\right )=\\frac{1}{x}-25\\) where \\( a\\neq b\\)  then \\( \\int_{1}^{2}f(x)dx\\) is <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-3)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{a^{2}-b^{2}}[a(ln2-25)+\\frac{47b}{2}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{a^{2}-b^{2}}[a(2ln2-25)-\\frac{47b}{2}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{a^{2}-b^{2}}[a(2ln2-25)+\\frac{47b}{2}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{a^{2}-b^{2}}[a(ln2-25)-\\frac{47b}{2}]\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{a^{2}-b^{2}}[a(ln2-25)+\\frac{47b}{2}]\\)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8554/gate2015-3-44#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>If the following system has non-trivial solution,<br> px+qy+rz=0 <br> qx+ry+pz=0 <br> rx+py+qz=0,<br> then which one of the following options is TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-3)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>p-q+r=0 or p=q=-r</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>p+q-r=0 or p=-q=r</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>p+q+r=0 or p=q=r</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>p-q+r=0 or p=-q=-r</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>p+q+r=0 or p=q=r</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8490/gate2015-3-42#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
